<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>#Japan on kasader.cc/</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/%23japan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in #Japan on kasader.cc/</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 19:08:47 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/%23japan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tags</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/tags/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 19:08:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/tags/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manners in Japan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/japan-etiquette/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 12:52:12 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/japan-etiquette/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are some very &lt;strong&gt;basic manners&lt;/strong&gt; to keep in mind while one is in Japan. In this section, I am going to outline some of the fundamental manners that you should keep in mind during your stay in Japan. If reading isn&amp;rsquo;t your thing, here is also a short (~12 min.) &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0GCuvcTI090&#34;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; you might watch instead to get an rough idea of what kinds of manners you should mind during your time in the Land of the Rising Sun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;rule-1-mind-personal-space&#34;&gt;Rule 1: Mind Personal Space! &lt;a href=&#34;#rule-1-mind-personal-space&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Make sure to always mind the personal space of others. This goes without saying in any case, but especially in Japan! Believe it or not, this also extends to your party as well. In Japan, PDA or &amp;ldquo;public displays of affection&amp;rdquo; are not considered typically in normal everyday (public) life. This means no handshakes, and instead bows. A short bow, in any case, will do the trick. I am sure you will be quite used to bowing before the end of your trip&amp;hellip;! Also, when boarding trains or cramped spaces, people will always make sure to switch their bookbags to the front of their bodies to make sure that they are not accidentally hitting anyone with it while moving inside of the train.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;rule-2-do-not-eat-or-drink-while-walking&#34;&gt;Rule 2: Do NOT Eat or Drink While Walking! &lt;a href=&#34;#rule-2-do-not-eat-or-drink-while-walking&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Japan, it is NOT acceptable to eat or drink while walking. While strange as it might sound, it is not done. This is to both maintain a clean public environment as well as not to inconvenience others around you. If you pick up food from a stall, store, or vending machine, try to drink it outside of the place that you got it, or stow it inside of a bag. If you would like to snack on something later, make sure to walk to the side of the road where you will not be in the way of others in order to enjoy your meal/drink!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;rule-3-no-shoes-inside&#34;&gt;Rule 3: No Shoes Inside! &lt;a href=&#34;#rule-3-no-shoes-inside&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Always make sure to be observant to see whether or not you need to remove your shoes when entering a building. If an establishment is shoeless, or always when entering someone&amp;rsquo;s home, you will need to remove your shoes when entering the building. There will be overshoes (often times) for you to slip into, as well as a box to keep your shoes in during your time inside. Remember, not all buildings require you to take off your shoes, but when they do, it should be obvious and easy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;rule-4-dont-play-with-your-chopsticks&#34;&gt;Rule 4: Don&amp;rsquo;t Play With Your Chopsticks! &lt;a href=&#34;#rule-4-dont-play-with-your-chopsticks&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t drop or fiddle too much with your chopsticks while eating and try to maintain good and proper etiquette. There are a few lesser known taboos as well, these are: (1) do not pass food from chopstick to chopstick; and (2) do not stick your chopsticks upright into food, or rice. Both of these practices are related to Japanese funerary rites, so try to refrain!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;rule-5-dont-tip&#34;&gt;Rule 5: Don&amp;rsquo;t Tip! &lt;a href=&#34;#rule-5-dont-tip&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is no tipping culture in Japan. In fact, tipping is considered rude; and more often than not, if you leave a tip, your waiter/waitress will try and return it to you thinking that you mistakenly left money at your table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;rule-6-no-public-phone-calls&#34;&gt;Rule 6: No Public Phone Calls! &lt;a href=&#34;#rule-6-no-public-phone-calls&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is considered to be rude to take phone calls in enclosed public spaces like restaurants or trains. In fact, in any public space it is best practice to not be loud, or even to talk much at all. Even packed trains are typically completely silent with only occasional conversations of utterances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;rule-7-dont-blow-your-nose&#34;&gt;Rule 7: Don&amp;rsquo;t Blow Your Nose! &lt;a href=&#34;#rule-7-dont-blow-your-nose&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you need to blow your nose, try and do it at home. It is considered rude and unsanitary in Japan to blow your nose in public (similar to someone farting in the U.S.). Instead, people will sniffle in to keep their snot from coming out. If you need to blow your nose, go to a bathroom or seek a place with less people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;rule-8-dont-litter&#34;&gt;Rule 8: Don&amp;rsquo;t Litter! &lt;a href=&#34;#rule-8-dont-litter&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Again, this should go without saying, however, it still must be said! There are very few trash cans in public in Japan. The expectation when you create trash is to keep it with you until you get home, or to throw it away in the trash can of the store that you got it from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;rule-9-dont-jaywalk&#34;&gt;Rule 9: Don&amp;rsquo;t Jaywalk! &lt;a href=&#34;#rule-9-dont-jaywalk&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wait until it is your turn to cross the street. Remember: jaywalking in the first step in a long, long series of steps to societal collapse (hahaha, I digress). Try to refrain from doing this, as it is looked down upon. Plus, let&amp;rsquo;s try and avoid any accidents to be had during your time overseas!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;rule-10-dont-stress-too-much-about-all-these-rules&#34;&gt;Rule 10: Don&amp;rsquo;t Stress Too Much About All These Rules! &lt;a href=&#34;#rule-10-dont-stress-too-much-about-all-these-rules&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;So long as you try your best, and make it clear to others that you are attempting to be polite despite perhaps not being used to the customs and manners of Japan. You will be just fine! Do your best to avoid disrupting the peace, and refrain from mistreating peoples and places while in a country which is not your home. If so, there will be no problems to be had! More than anything, make sure to enjoy your time in Japan, and take it easy. It&amp;rsquo;s a vacation, after all!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
