<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Creative Writing on kasader.cc/</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/creative-writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Creative Writing on kasader.cc/</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 12:42:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/creative-writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dreaming of the French Press</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/french-press/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 12:42:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/french-press/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;lofty-dreams-of-a-french-press&#34;&gt;Lofty Dreams of (a) French Press &lt;a href=&#34;#lofty-dreams-of-a-french-press&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the title implies, I have found myself recently thinking about getting a French press. One of the key reasons being that, I prefer, if possible, to [[Modernity, a Technological Nightmare|not have my appliances require electricity]]. A French press requires no outside help to function excluding the simple action of (French) pressing; and from an entirely (subjective) aesthetic view, they look nice. I (currently) believe that owning a French press would naturally incentive healthy coffee drinking habits (invoke moderation, as not doing so would require greater labor on the part of myself). The press also yet remains a far more affordable option as opposed to the full-blown electric coffee maker as well. In spite of not having much experience in the way of the habitual coffee brew, I do have sense of my personal preferences on the &amp;ldquo;things&amp;rdquo; of life (the choice of buying, and using, a French press being one of these many things). One other great thing about a French press (although not unique to one), is that I will have to buy and grind my own coffee beans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The transition to the French Press does not stop at its mere adoption. This is just a single phase of my idealized greater shift in modal enjoyment. That of of the savoring of coffee. To get to the point: I hint at the adoption, too, of the coffee grinder. I have a strong desire to freshly grind my own coffee beans prior to coffee consumption. Supposedly, freshly ground coffee beans (as compared to pre-ground coffee grounds that one may buy at the store) have a certain freshness to them which aids in overall coffee quality: its scent, color, and flavor. I desire to enjoy these pleasantries inherit to laborious process. Through a poetic-worldview we might see that the very act of self-preparation is indeed the conceptual &amp;ldquo;freedom&amp;rdquo; manifest. I, for one, believe that within the very act of creation (in the Hermetic sense) therein present is meditative. O to heal the soul. O to drink coffee. There are very few things in life that actually smell better than freshly ground coffee beans. I would love that smell in the morning. The fact that more people do not grind their beans I personally find this to be rather offensive. As for the French press, however, we shall see. I cannot wait to savor the great fragrance. O to wonder of ye freshly ground and delicious brew; for I am the Brewmeister. I love a good ground bean. &amp;ldquo;Not my bean, not my problem,&amp;rdquo; that&amp;rsquo;s what I say.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am also deep in thought considering many other forms of enjoying my coffee as well. This ranges from a large machine, perhaps one of those large metal machines that can brew a fine espresso shot. I hear these machines cost a fortune: the seven jewels and treasures, as well as many gold (chocolate) coins to obtain. The &amp;ldquo;civil&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;man&amp;rdquo; seems to enjoy these toys, but he will not fool me. I am an honest man. I am a simple man. I shall stick to my French Press, for their toys are more toil and trouble than they are worth their weight in gold (&lt;strong&gt;NOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: a lot of gold).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;actual-thoughts-post-french-press&#34;&gt;Actual Thoughts Post-French Press &lt;a href=&#34;#actual-thoughts-post-french-press&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
